Andrés Michelangelli

Project Engineer | Data Analytics | Business Intelligence

Date of birth: 05/17/1992 Address: Rio de Janeiro, Brazil Phone number: +55 (21) 990456300 E-mail: andresmiche17@gmail.com

Web: https://www.linkedin.com/in/andr%C3%A9s-michelangelli/

Profile

Mechanical Engineer with international work experience developing multidisciplinary engineering projects, with a strong focus on project management and data analytics approaches. Experience in developing and integrating projects to meet long-term business goals, by cultivating relationships and communication across various teams and stakeholders.

- Over six years of work experience in multidisciplinary engineering projects.
- Skills in Data Analytics and Business Intelligence (Power BI, SQL, Python and Excel).
- Proficiency in English (upper-intermediate), Portuguese (advanced) and Spanish (native).
- Legally able to work in Brazil.

Education

2021 – 2023	MBA in Project Manag	ement - Univers	idade de São	Paulo. Brazil
-------------	----------------------	-----------------	--------------	---------------

<u>Description:</u> USP Project Management MBA in accordance with PMBOK® guidelines, with a strong

focus on predictive, adaptive/agile and hybrid approaches.

2021 - 2021 Mechanical Engineering Validation - Universidade Federal Fluminense, Brazil

<u>Description:</u> Mechanical Engineering degree validated by Universidade Federal Fluminense, in

accordance with Brazil's MEC standards.

2009 – 2015 Bachelor's Mechanical Engineering - Universidad de Carabobo, Venezuela

<u>Thesis:</u> Design of new structural profiles from commercial HEB structural beams profiles through

Finite Elements Analysis.

Key Technical Skills

BI and Data Analytics: Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Power BI, Power Query, DAX.

Programming Languages: Python, SQL, VBA.

Other skills: MS Project, Project Management, Microsoft Office, Languages (English, Portuguese, and Spanish), Business Operations, Strategy.

Soft skills: Problem-solving, Decision making, Strong analytic skills, Adaptability, Teamwork, Time management, Critical thinking, Communication, Commitment.

Work Experience

11/2021 – present RADIX Engineering and Software, Brazil

<u>Position:</u> Mechanical Engineer I.

Field: Oil &Gas, Energy, and Industrial Projects.

Function: • Analyze project data to develop and verify documentation.

· Support project coordination with data-driven planning, budgeting, and

forecasting.

· Understand client needs and deliver data-driven solutions and insights for digital

transformation projects.

Achievement: Led a high-profile project for an international client, overseeing a team of 10,

leveraging data analytics and business intelligence tools.

Key Projects: • Valves Human Factor Study for FPSO units; Yinson Production (Singapore).

• Brazil Assets Reliability Assessment (Offshore Units); Trident Energy (Brazil).

02/2021 - 11/2021 SANDECH Consulting Engineering Ltda., Brazil

<u>Position:</u> Engineering Analyst.

Field: Oil &Gas, Energy, and Industrial Projects.

Function: • Elaborate and verify project documentation.

Conduct detailed engineering projects and field surveys.

Achievement: • Perform first detailed project in Brazil for a high-profile client (Shell) in the gas

industry, with tight deadlines.

Key Project:
R2D2-B Route 2 Delivery to Bridge UTGCAB; Shell/Petrobras (Brazil).

04/2018 - 01/2020 AESA - YPF, Argentina

Position: Piping Specialist.

<u>Field:</u> Oil & Gas, Energy, Manufacturing and Engineering.

Function: • Develop engineering projects using CAD tools.

Support manufacturing and operations teams with detailed engineering data.

Achievement: • Selected by YPF, the largest energy company in Argentina, for a role among 6000

candidates nationwide.

• Achieved a 50% reduction in engineering processing time on a \$180 million

project through data optimization.

• Malvinas Flare System Upgrading Project (MFSUP); Pluspetrol (Perú).

• 3 Combined Cycles for Energy Generation; MSU Energy (Argentina).